Hi, Veronic.
Hello, how are you doing?
I'm very well, how are you?
Am I pronouncing your name right first of all?
I'll do that.
That's brilliant.
You did very well.
No.
I thought I'd go in and then we'll work from there.
Exactly.
High confidence is like How are you this morning?
I'm doing well.
I'm doing well, not too bad.
Better than the wet outside.
Like it looks absolutely horrendous.
I was walking home yesterday evening and I just got caught in a rain and I was just like miserable, you know, just like oh yeah, I don't know.
The worst part is if you have like uh shoes that are not set for the rain.
There's nothing worse than just having like wet feet all morning, which is the situation I'm in at the moment because I wore some like kinda old and probably should be replaced bands and now they're just soaked.
So my life is crap from this way.
Oh no.
Do you know what?
I I I've been there, so I feel I feel for you.
I actually I I went and ended sales, I got some some new shoes, I bought some hookers, and I like advertised like they were like water resistant.
They are not.
Like they're not.
And I'm like, Yeah, shouldn't fall for that crap.
I don't think.
It doesn't make it so.
Yeah, but how are you doing?
Apart from the wet feet.
Yeah, not too bad.
Not too bad.
I'm in the office today, which is why it's kind of just like a soulless room.
They're they're decorating this part of the office.
It's like one of the newer meeting rooms.
They have put stuff on the walls, which is good.
But um yeah, it's uh all the other meeting rooms are a little bit more interesting, and I'm gonna have to put the one that's just like picture.
Oh, it is like, yeah, I I do I like the purple.
It's quite um it's quite different.
Okay, okay.
So purple is the colour of the brand.
Purple's the colour of the brand for the yeah, the main overarching business, and then there's little sort of can you sort of see the little motifs on the wall?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
That's the publishing is one with waveforms for audio.
It's all very moves nicely as well.
So yeah.
Um in Bermansey, so yeah, quite central, which is good.
Um I'm working at Bloomberg, so I'm lucky to walk to Bloomberg.
They are around Bank Station.
Yeah, they are based around Bank Station.
So it takes me like depending on how quick I walk, 35 minutes.
So which is which is good.
It helps with like keeping me active.
I don't have to go to the gym, you know, saving money and being active.
It's like, yay.
Guess life sorted.
Power walk in everyone.
Exactly.
Yeah.
One thing before I get cracking.
The um are you happy if I just turn on Copilot?
It helps uh Lauren with any notes that we have.
Yeah, transfer.
Yeah, that's fine, that's fine, don't worry.
Lovely.
We have to get consent.
Consent is important, so it is it's one of these weird things, isn't it?
Like, it's helpful, but it's like, well, you also don't want to freak people out.
Like all the time.
Just like Matt started transcription, you'd be like, what?
So I I I'll just give you sort of like a little bit of background to uh like what we'll run through today, and um a little bit of background to me, the role, the team, Bauer.
Um, I imagine Lauren's done a little bit of it with you already.
Yes.
Um, she's sent over some sort of summary notes, obviously have your CV, and then she's also provided us um with a set of questions that we'll run through.
Um there's some more steering points, just they're not like super intense, but they're more sort of just to keep us on the the straight and narrow as we go through.
Um sound good?
Sounds perfect.
Lovely.
So uh yeah, I'm Matt.
I work in the um AI joint capability team or JCT.
Um is just gone 150 years old as a company uh last year.
Um they have three lines of business of which we sit in audio.
There's also publishing, there's also outdoor, which we acquired last year, which was Clear Channel previously.
Um so they're now Bauer outdoor.
So we have outdoor advertising, publishing, and audio, which is all of our radio stations.
The JCTs, uh the drunk capability teams, there's an AI one commercial, and a few other ones, and they're essentially designed to sort of be a nexus of capability with some sort of subject matter experts in them, and we work across all nine of our audio markets.
So that's the UK, Portugal, Ireland, all of the Nordics, so Denmark, Norway, Sweden, Finland, Poland, and Slovakia.
Um Bow is also headquartered in Hamburg.
That's where Yvonne Bauer, the owner of the company, lives, um, and runs the company from.
So we're still a privately owned company, which is quite cool because it means that we don't have what we have to prove value and stuff, but there's not shareholders breathing down our necks at all times.
There is one shareholder, so she wants to keep the business going, and that sort of breeds a nice sort of innovative creative environment, which is cool.
Um so it's a kind of unique place to work.
There's lots of different things all going on across lots of different companies.
Um, and our team is designed to act as consultants and experts for AI across all of the uh nine markets, uh, and also take all of their wants, needs and wishes into account and deliver against them.
So in the I always sort of compare it to like an IT team, but not an IT team.
Where uh where the markets would ask something of an IT team, they would go, Yes, of course, sir, thank you, sir, and then they're done.
We can take a request and we act much more like an agency and go, yes, I see what you're trying to get to, what's the problem you're trying to solve here, and we recommend this, this, and this.
Um, so fundamentally we are there to help, but we're also there to guide and hold hands, especially in AI, um, because they know they want it, they know they want to do stuff with it, but they don't know necessarily what it's like big and sexy, but they don't know why sometimes not always, there's uh a lot of cool stuff happening in some of the markets.
We've got like AI traffic in Finland and news and weather, so there's pockets of innovation, and our job is to put that together.
Um and so the vision sort of for this role is um oh, actually, just briefly, on the team, there's myself, uh we have Nimit and Joshua who are also um uh senior product and delivery managers.
So um we essentially are the ones that make stuff, translate requirements into things, engage with the stakeholders, deliver workshops, it's kind of a Swiss Army knife style um sort of role.
We have Catherine who's uh the AI director, and that forms the strategy and product team that sit in London.
Um then we also have Pavel, who's our research and development lead.
He is based in Warsaw in Poland, and he has got a team, will have a team in the next two months of uh three engineers initially with a forthcoming later down the line.
So we've basically gone from a team of two, which was myself and Catherine, to a team of eight in about three or four months.
Um so what used to pass for um sort of organization, no longer will pass for organization because everyone in the team is fairly competent, we all just get on and do.
We don't have a lot of time historically for standardizing and productizing and making sure that our processes make sense, we're communicating adequately to the business, um, we're sort of doing the all of the other stuff around it that comes from uh being in a big corporate.
So the team itself functions a lot like a startup, and we service a large corporate entity.
So there are things that we need to do like tax um uh tax compliance stuff, um standardizing our product process, that would be good.
Tracking our work, reporting to the SLT, all of that.
And so brings me on to a little bit of the vision for this role.
Essentially, we're looking for like the operational backbone of our team, someone who can keep us sort of pointed in the right direction on the straight and narrow, professionalize what we do, manage noise, help us prove value, and sort of be a sort of a hand to hold in that process.
Um, in the sense of we're all quite good at doing the work, we're probably not as good as we should be, in all honesty, about making sure that it's all tracked and communicated and uh standardized.
And if we could do that with somebody who knows what they're doing, then we would be able to work faster, better and stronger, and whatever the fourth thing was in the Darth Con.
So that's a bit of a whistle stop tour.
Um anything new, unexpected doesn't make sense.
I realize I sort of just threw a whole bunch of information at you.
Everything makes sense, it's very much in line with what Lauren basically explained, and she very much said like it's quite interesting because you are operating like almost like a startup, but within like a large corporation.
Um, so that's quite interesting.
And um, like I know oftentimes it looks like the bit corps have figured it out, but to be honest, like where I'm coming from, like even within Blumberg, so much isn't even yet figured out, even within my department, you just have to go in and be like, okay, this isn't standardized, there's an organisation, organization, people do how people think they should do it, you know, oftentimes.
So, and then people do it differently, and then there's mistakes happening, and then oftentimes an escalation comes your way.
So, it's yeah, I'm very familiar with that kind of like environment.
But it's also exciting because it's it's nice to have that freedom to grow and to kind of like steer wherever you want and go inhead and kind of like um have ownership of like how you want to shape it, rather than just being like thrown into like, oh, does this your role these are your objectives?
Off you go, just stay on a path, don't move left or right.
Yeah, exactly that.
And it's very much not it.
There's I think the only thing that might be daunting is that there isn't really a path to to trade.
Yeah.
Sort of have opinions, ask us why we've done stuff.
There's probably not a very good reason why.
Um so like having uh having opinions and coming in and basically it the opportunity is to sort of come in and work all not from nothing.
We do have like a full roadmap, we have it all in Monday.com.
I know you I think TV says you have experience with Monday.com and sort of coming in and taking what we have and putting it pulling apart and throwing away what doesn't work.
We're not precious people about anything, um and stuff is that I think that one of the primary goals for the person would be sort of inquisitive and kind of not afraid to just go and talk to people and get stuck in figure stuff out.
And um, yeah, that's sort of I think what would be one of the key things we'd need.
Okay, interesting.
Cool.
So um I've like I said, I've got like a little uh list of questions.
Um I'll run through a couple of them and then um yeah, they'll I'll leave at least sort of like 10-15 minutes at the end for any questions that you've got, anything that I can help with.
So um the first one that I've got here is um essentially uh a large part of this role would be obviously the process part that we've spoken about, but also managing how we handle inbound and new ad hoc requests.
So um we've got 121 things to deliver this year on our roadmap in 2022.
But obviously, new things are gonna crop up.
AIG over time.
Right now, people might just message me or engineers directly or send round emails.
If you were to sort of start tomorrow, how do you think you'd go about setting up a proper front door process for inbound requests?
Um so what I'm hearing basically is like a free-for-all.
So people come to you, they are like, okay, I need this done, and then someone else comes in the afternoon wants you to get this done as well.
The way um I would look at it is kind of thinking about it, what's important, what do we absolutely need to work on?
What is like what is our strategy of the department and anything big that comes in, does it align with it?
Um, and then kind of like going from there, we're kind of like almost like tiering the different requests.
So everything obviously people have good ideas, but different ideas may be less like valuable like immediately.
So kind of thinking about what do I need to get done within the next month?
How does it help me with the team?
How does it align us with the broader like this department strategy, but then also before with the broader like um corporation strategy in terms of like how would I go on and um making it like foundational?
I would create like if possible, like a ticketing system.
So people come in, it doesn't just come to you or to someone else, it would come through like a a first line of frontier.
Um that person either would like manually go and look at um across different criteria.
How does it match up?
Does it match up to what um the strategy the value the impact that we want to have?
And then depending on like the different requirements, criteria, um it then falls into a tier one, tier two, tier three, and then it would kind of like go further through the like the journey, might might make its way to you, and then you would be like looking at it, okay.
Again, maybe a different set of criteria, um, matching it up again, seeing like okay, what is most valuable?
So that's kind of like how I would approach that.
Um I had a different thing as well, I forgot.
Um yeah, might come back.
If it comes back, just shout at me.
We can circle back.
That sounds sounds good to me.
Um excellent, thank you.
Um, so uh we obviously briefly have spoken about Monday.com, so we use it quite a lot now to sort of report our work up to the SLT, trust where things are at.
Um and I wondered uh if there was sort of a specific way that you like to set things up in it, if how you like to work in it, and do you see it more for driving work forward um or mainly as like a tracking tool?
Um and if you had any examples of times that you've designed anything within it.
I think it can be both.
It really depends on how you use it.
I think um it gets tricky when people don't know how to use a specific tool or how to use like Monday.com.
If our consensus is we use it as a project management tracker, then everyone should use it as such and not as like a different tool or different like um reason why we are using it.
So that's kind of like where where I would start.
Why are we, why do we need it?
What's the purpose of it?
What is helping for us?
And maybe also looking like, oh, maybe we are not using it for a project management tool, but we are using it just to keep on top of certain things or have people log into different um work items.
But maybe then we look at it and you're like, oh, it's actually not helpful to us.
Maybe there's something else that we can use.
So kind of like thinking like what's what's the biggest issue that you're trying to solve with Monday.com, and then figuring out a is it solving the issue?
And if it is, what can we do to make it better to help you?
Where are the pain points?
Um I would speak with you, speak with the team and figure out like, okay, what do you find tricky?
Um, is it just like it's a free-for-all, people just need to track it individually, but then it falls off the radar and people actually don't do it, and then maybe your your boss looks at it and they are like looking at it and they're like, Well, nothing is updated, what's happening here?
And it doesn't offer a lot of visibility.
So maybe what you would need is one person to kind of like keep um keep that tracker in in check, talk to the different people on the different projects that they are working on, and be like, okay, where are we at here?
Can you help me here?
What's the status here?
Just having someone who's kind of like driving the accountability and the ownership.
But again, it depends what people need, you know, like it depends if that's if that's the issue.
I had, for example, in my team, we had um specialists, they were kind of like project managers, and they um sometimes mistakes happen, and then it would be escalated to me.
And what I've noticed there was an increase in climate mistakes that were happening, and those mistakes they weren't tracked anywhere, so no one would take ownership of it no one would knew is that now solved you know basically you've got a client they can't trade anymore and people are just like well not my problem you know so it's just kind of like um I put in a formal way of like tracking these issues why did the issue come up and who's owning that issue so that it's visible to the whole global team that we are actually tracking it and also kind of like learning from that so that's the way I would I approach like Monday.com.
I've used Monday.com previously um at Big Burn they were also a publishing house and it was kind of like working with the commissioning editors because they were speaking to the um people to to get new work online but then no one was actually tracking anything and then we would have like our our weekly meetup and people would be like oh I've got this and this and this on the line but nowhere else to track it keep track of it people would forget who did I chat to what else do I need to do so that's where I brought like Monday.com in more as a form of project tracker in terms of seeing like okay where's people where are people at where is that item moving is it now within this team or does it move is it moving to a different team and then the ownership kind of like um moves with that.
Got you so sort of um couple of potential things that you could use it for is the project tracking element but also there was almost like a sort of risk slash issue tracker sort of thing because that's another part of uh which I think is like down number eight or something like that.
Um which was sort of about um yeah, keeping like risk logs, all of that sort of stuff um up to date.
Our our uh what would I say our approach to that is probably the best word.
Our approach to that so far has been uh if we are cognizant of a risk, we should deal with it rather than write it down.
Yeah, that's been working so far, but obviously there are longer term ones in terms of uh you know, if there are sort of exposure within a client relationship or any of that sort of stuff that I am increasingly seeing the need for this sort of thing.
So I think that that's only set to increase.
So that's good that um you've got some some sort of previous experience on that one as well.
And also just to add the risks.
Sometimes it's something that might potentially become an issue, but may not be an issue just now.
So just about like almost keeping taps of on stuff, especially when there's a lot of like moving items, um, with risk, it's like okay, again, chewing the risk, how important is it?
Is that do I anticipate that like tomorrow is actually gonna be like uh like chaos basically because I didn't solve it today, or is it actually actually just a little bit of a smaller issue that we can handle like down the line?
Um, and then it also gives like in my mind I I like these things because it gives me a way to like not freak out about like what I have in front of me, but kind of understand okay, this is something that doesn't need to be done today, but I can it's locked in, I don't forget about it, so I can always come back to it.
Yeah, no, that makes a lot of sense.
Um, sort of yeah, filing it away so that it's still burning there on the back of the brain.
Excellent.
Um, and sort of on sort of a slight aside to that, obviously, on sort of the administrative tasks, uh, we have um we have a f a small amount of admin directly in the team um at the moment, but um outside of that we have to sort of feed into procurement processes, we have to keep evidence of service across all nine markets for tax reasons.
So we're basically the UK, we recharge our services across the markets, mainly quite mainly I believe for RD tax credits.
Um so we we actually have to maintain a log of everything we're doing, um, which are like really really important stuff, but they can be quite um like admin heavy in and and and and and time consuming and not necessarily standardized.
So our evidence of service could be an email, it could be a sign off on a document, etc.
So in those sorts of tasks, I wondered two things.
Um, sort of like how would you sort of stay motivated and organized when dealing with that part of the the job um and how you try to remove that burden from like the developers or product team, etc.
Um how to stay motivated?
Um I think with any job you always have like some kind of admin bug to do.
I've got a lot of admin work to do, um, and I just oftentimes it's just about like getting it out there, just doing it.
You also understanding like the broader, the broader reason why are we doing this?
Um a lot of like what I'm doing is also like tracking things, keeping people on taps, and then I I like to work with delayed messages, so I keep track of myself and be like, okay, I can't handle it today, it can wait till tomorrow, I'll send a delayed message, and then tomorrow when I come in, I'm like, oh yeah, need to get this sorted.
So kind of like putting that in place, and then um yeah, uh like these things just need to get done.
I think sometimes because you were speaking like you you're working like within AI, it's it's can then again could that be automated?
You know, is there a way that these kind of like um if that evidence of work comes in and it's like maybe like it's hashtag in a certain way, and then you would have like, I don't know, an a certain like um AI tool that would go into your emails, drag it into a different folder, and then I would just have them all sitting in my folder, and then it's just about either like going and looking at them and then um archiving them appropriately, or even like giving the tool the possibility to even like automate it um itself, basically, and in terms of like taking the workload away from yourself and from the engineers, it's about like being that being that enabler.
So if you are guys are doing it, I think I would come in and be like, okay, what are you currently doing?
Um how is it how are you currently solving it?
And then kind of like taking that work off you guys and then establishing as well, like um a framework that the the transition period is basically also going well, so that it's not just like oh few of them you still handle, and then a few of them I handle, and then it's kind of like okay, but who's really owning it?
So kind of like really creating a good transition period where I'm kind of like would fully own that process, and then like seeing can we kind of create some kind of automation around Dart?
Can we kind of like archive it automatically, or is it just something that that needs to get done at the end of the wood of the day.
Yeah for sure.
And yeah this this is sort of like a an end of the year sort of thing but it's one of those things that we save ourselves a whole load of time if we just get ahead of it.
So yeah it's something to be cognizant of I think coming in it's a unique challenge of the multi-market sort of approach we have.
And I guess not deleting emails like sometimes what we have like I I do we get a lot of um a lot of updates.
It's like yeah every day I come to like 300 different emails and it's just like sometimes I just save my emails you know it's just like I've got a function I save them into my notes and then I do a control F search and then there they are you know and I can qu quickly search by if a keyword and then still know okay the information is still there.
It's not like I've lost it or I don't know where to find it.
Yeah of course yeah um it's outlook based it's all Microsoft based okay so if you're familiar with that then you can sort of set up outlook rules and things like that if if you need to um but another part of that would be almost like working to standardize what comes in to work as well.
So it's sort of how we what's our standard process for kicking off a project is there sort of like major milestones we need to hit that sort of thing sign off points all of that sort of stuff is being done on an ad hoc basis by myself different product managers uh but probably just needs sitting down and going this thing, then this thing.
Yeah.
It's just it's happening, it's just not being documented.
So yeah.
What so uh a slightly different question.
So that's quite a lot of process and all of the underlying stuff and tracking.
Um so uh one thing that we'll need to do going forward is uh produce a sort of AI impact report for the senior leadership team.
Yeah, um so if I was to sort of uh a little bit of background before I throw you into this version, we have a product called Bower AI Chat, which is like an internal version of Chat GPT, and it allows for people to use all of the latest models, completely agnostic of platform, and throw anything into it, so confidential client information, that sort of stuff.
It's all housed in our own secure server in Sweden, etc.
So one of the things that we do is monitor like usage data of that, how many people are using it.
So if I was to sort of give you a set of raw usage data from the last two months, and a few sort of like anecdotal quotes from users of things we've built in the platform, uh one, I suppose would you be comfortable if I just didn't have the celebration of stuff?
And uh how would you go about sort of structuring that data and information to make it exciting for a CEO or a CTO to read?
Um I would be comfortable with Excel.
I've got a lot of like we track everything, so everything then my team touches, everything that is being processed and assessed.
Everything is checked through like metrics and data and information, and uh like I on a weekly basis are there in like my my Excel sheet and looking at like okay, how is the top performer performing?
How many items are they doing compared to someone else?
Or what is like our biggest increase of like tickets coming in or items being reviewed, items being handled basically.
So very comfortable with that.
I think with like any kind of data, um, I'm almost looking at it like a detective.
What am I trying to find out?
You know, like I think with with the data is like, what is like what's my argument almost?
Like, I've I've got a an idea in my head, and the data I kind of use it to almost um confirm my argument, or if I can't find a confirmation, deny it.
So if you gave me a set of like um Excel sheets and usage data as well as like some commentary, I would be looking at like okay, how how many people are using it, how long are they using it, um, is there any differences between different regions?
Is there any differences between different departments, and then kind of like trying to filter it, filtering it down, and then um with that kind of information that I have.
Obviously, in this team, my objective would be to make AI look good.
So making it look like people are using it, you know, it's not like a waste of of value, waste of like um time and uh money that people are putting into it.
So ultimately, I would be looking at it, okay, where are like my plus point on it, and then being like, okay, this is like really interesting, what I've noticed, and kind of framing into um a value pack, and like, okay, this is the impact that it has, and then framing it like that to the to the senior stakeholders, and then anything that I noticed, actually, we could do better, this is actually isn't really good.
Kind of coming up already with like how would I solve this issue?
So, kind of like not going to the executive leadership and being like, Ah, no one is using this tool that you have created and that you're spending so much money on.
Ah, well, you know, but I kind of being like, okay, people are using it like that.
Um, there's a huge um opportunity for people to use it more, and kind of like being like, oh, in order to increase the usage of it, we are doing XYZ, and this is what we are anticipating in terms of like um the users to increase people to use it, or different use cases.
I think, especially if like these AI tools, oftentimes it's just like it's a behavioral change, and it's like people don't really know when to use it or how to use it.
Oftentimes, what I see in my team is like people use it for to write emails, and then it like you know that it's written by AI, and then you're like, This is not how to use it, you know, and then kind of training people, it's a tool, use it as a tool, it's not there to like replace you and your your skill sets and all the good things that the human being brings to the table.
Yeah, no, exactly, and that's a lot of the edge.
So, another part of our remit is AI education across all nine markets, of which the nine markets there's a probably well, it's just in audio, about 3,000 employees, um, and we have eight, so we're also responsible for upskilling them nine markets, seven languages, and making sure that they are all sort of getting to a point where they are comfortable and AI enabled is the mode that we're using where it's there, they can have it if they want it.
Again, it's fundamentally creative business as well.
So, there are parts of it that we don't want to be replacing people with like replacing presenters on air with AI, who's gonna listen to an AI presenter, maybe overnight for a low-value slot, but it's not a priority.
So that's another part of it is the training piece.
Just whilst we're on uh this sort of communicating the um SLT, I think I saw something, I think it was in the notes from Lauren, maybe that you had set up a uh like your own GPT training chatbot.
Um then also used like some value metrics to communicate why you would need that to your CF CFO or um to the head of the department, yes.
So what I chatted with Lauren about was um I created a custom GPT.
So basically we had a quite new team, and people were just kind of like um if they didn't find the answer, they would just be like, okay, I'll wait for they want you to come over and kind of like help me out.
And like I would be busy and I'd be like, Yeah, I'll I'll help you, and then I'll forgot about it, and then two hours later, and then it kind of like delayed a lot of the business, and especially if you've got a very young team, it's like it's not very efficient to to run your department like that.
So what I did is in conjunction with creating like a trainer um role, I also created like a custom GPT.
So all the training material we kind of put it into there, we made sure that it was all correct, and then we we trained that GPT kind of like up to um um match all the questions that they have.
So if someone would be uh asking a question and the GPT doesn't know it, it wouldn't give you like it wouldn't hallucinate and give you something like that.
You you you it was wouldn't be right.
So it would always kind of like reference it with the training material.
So that's that's what I did and that's what I kind of like advocated for and um that's what kind of like with that we saved a lot of time and um I shared that with like the broader leadership of in the department and yeah so that's that that was pretty cool.
And and was it you making all of it as well so like did you sort of learn how to create correct and all of that sort of stuff yes correct in terms like rag and hallucinations and all of that sort of stuff.
Yes so I'm I'm not an AI expect so I'm not gonna basically recover your question which isn't on the list which is how do you feel about AI in general?
I feel good about it like I feel like it's good about it by the way I do I like I've I've um I like I have vibe coded my own apps just out of interest you know I've played around with like um clot code I've used like the the Google AI studio builder so like as a non-techie I'm I'm coming from like English lit background you know I'm not I'm not a coder I I don't know but it's quite empowering to go and just to do something just for fun like for for Christmas time I built like um a gift search kind of like app and it was just like a fun we thing where people would type in like the person that they wanted to buy the gift for and like who they are their age and like kind of like um what they're interested in and it would kind of like through Gemini find like specific gifts that people might be enjoying.
So it was just like a kind of fun interactive thing.
Um but it's it's a tool like that's what I tell my team.
I I wouldn't I wouldn't give it power over like my emails and sending emails to like my stakeholders or creating like if I created like um an impact email or uh what we have done in the last like three months I wouldn't say to like chat GPT off you go now create it because it would just come up with like random stuff and yeah it would just go off the rail so I use it as a uh as a tool and yeah as a place where I draft my stuff or I kind of like use it to if I've got an idea and I like I don't have anyone to bounce my ideas off with I'll be like hey I've got this idea what do you think about us can you be critical and and so forth yeah.
Yeah awesome yeah that's cool um it's interesting that you're you're sort of so like gone so deep into the holding middle products part of it rather than um sort of yeah I don't know any any other particular aspect of it I I've tried I did build like a little like nutrition tracky thing in the new year just out of interest.
Again using GMP um and yeah it's crazy um I do quite like what uh on well X now I assume it's a bin fire but um seeing people who are like I vibe coded this and now it's got 15 billion monthly annual recurring revenue and you're like yeah and then you follow the thread for a little bit and they're like I made a change and now everything's broken I don't know how to fix it.
Yes yeah yeah yeah a hundred percent and I think also like it's very misleading these people who say like it's a I created like a million dollar business because I put up some websites, like no, you definitely did not because I wasn't able to do that.
Like it's that it isn't that easy.
So it's yeah, you still need the human being, but it's nice where it can lead you, and it's like um it's an enabler, as you as you said, yeah.
Awesome.
And so um, sort of on a little bit of like the AI literacy piece, one of the things that we're doing in the first half of this year is designing and developing and making um an AI school.
So that'll be sort of like a um a toolbox on SharePoint as tools that they can use, pre-approved things, things to experiment with.
If you have this use case, use this.
It will also be a set of webinars that we're producing, it will also be workshops that uh like myself or another one of the project uh project managers will run, and that will probably be in person in one of the markets.
Um, and again, my question here is annoyingly twofold.
Um so um I saw I think that you've also done uh a training program uh within your role.
So I wondered firstly, uh how you approach that um from uh knowing what to put in it perspective and also separating it between people of low literacy and people of high literacy, and then I've got a second one, but we'll start with that.
Um I've done a lot of training.
Um just thinking do you like do you want to know about like how would I start from like from scratch to putting on like a training program like there's nothing?
Or do you want to know like how would I train someone up?
Um, I think probably like how would you approach knowing what to put in the training program?
Okay, does that make sense?
That makes sense.
A team of people that might need to know something, like how would you approach going, okay, we should focus on intro to prompting.
We shouldn't focus on building your own app, that sort of thing.
Yeah.
Maybe for some people, I don't know.
So the way I would approach this is maybe like again, with like what what you ask about the other question is about the data.
So looking at the data, how people are using it, and then where are most people using it?
Where's maybe like a missed opportunity that they are not using it, and then kind of like working from there.
Oftentimes it's also um I like to speak to people, so just understanding, like, okay, if you're not using it or you think it's it's rubbish, why do you think that?
And some people are quite strong about AI, I think, especially like in the creative industry.
So just like kind of like hearing out what their concerns are and then kind of like trying to just show them maybe one way of using AI or one way of like sharing like a way of like, hey, this could be your life a little bit uh easier, and it's not about replacing your role as writer, but it's about like managing your inbox, for example.
So it's kind of like about about that, looking where people are and then taking them into like that next zone.
I wouldn't, I think there's something called like very fancy word, but like um zone of proximity or something like that, zone of development proximity, and it basically just means like you are in your little zone and you can't take someone like out like into the five next zones because like that would overwhelm that person.
So I would just be like, okay, what's the next closest zone that I could bring them into?
And then and then sharing that with them.
In terms of like in in a SharePoint, obviously, you have people coming in from a lot of different backgrounds and a lot of different like where they're at.
But so I would check where's where's the majority of my my users, where are they sitting, and what would be the most useful thing for them to show to see and to share and to learn, and that's where I would build it out.
So not focusing on the edge cases, like on the people who are um AR fanatics and building apps, as you said, and then big showing them prompts on how to do that, um, but kind of like being like, where's the majority of the people sitting, and then kind of like taking them and kind of like trying to take them on the journey of like learning about AI and sharing with them, like okay, these are different use cases of how you can do it.
That makes a lot of sense to me, and sort of on that as well.
Obviously, I mentioned we operate across nine different markets, can uh and three time zones.
Finland's two hours ahead, everyone has an hour ahead.
Portugal and us are the same, and so is Ireland.
Um that can make kind of scheduling training, tracking attendance for employees, all sort of like a logistical challenge.
And I wondered if you sort of had any experience of managing coordination at that sort of scale before across multiple markets, and how you sort of keep track of who's done what um it's very difficult, it's a really like it's a big issue.
Also, here we do something called like um sales trainment.
So, what I've noticed is that um the salespeople oftentimes they come to us and they ask us questions, and then I'm like, you should know that, you know.
So it's oftentimes like, and then the team gets quite frustrated because they have to answer questions where they are like, Well, why do they come to me?
They should know how like the contract is built, because that's what they're selling to their clients so they should know and what I've created is basically um a session a training session for all sales reps but focusing on newer account managers so anyone new that comes in they have to go through that mandatory um sales training and we started out like every month we had a session on a Monday morning and we we would make it mandatory and people were expected to join however six months in we noticed like people weren't really joining they were joining from Zoom they were clicking on different things and then also like our sales force they are doing a lot of like traveling so people sometimes wouldn't be in the office and then it would be kind of like stepping back okay what is the most useful kind of like and then what I did is checking with them with the sales CEOs and being like okay we've got this we've noticed this and they they they they gave us a lot of like um they wanted this to go forward as well and so they were like okay maybe Monday mornings isn't the most useful time so what other other time can we do you know what other um days can we take apart and then we we agreed on Wednesdays so we were kind of like looking and working with them on terms of like what is the best time to take their um out of their schedule we create we um focused on Wednesdays we also focused on that we wouldn't train the new account managers just right after they they join Bloomberg but we would give them like three months where they could kind of like um get accustomed to how we are doing our work, how what is actually their work and within sales and not just bombard them with contracts when they haven't even spoken to a single client.
So we kind of like we're like, okay, let's wait a little bit.
So once the cohort comes in, we wait three months, then we push them through that like training session.
And also we moved away from like doing it every month to a quarterly basic.
So because we were feeling like a bit like it's a bit overwhelming to do it every month.
So we kind of like stepped away from that in terms of tracking what we do is like a QR code.
So people have to sign up for it.
And then that information comes to us.
That information comes to me.
And then once they have signed up and they also attend to the the the class, they have to um scan the QR code and once they've scanned the QR code, they get logged as they have attended us.
That's and then we we just we are very cheeky.
We give them to KRK at the end of the session.
So people can't drop off.
Um but yeah that's how we kind of like take note of the attendance, how many people are attending but all in all like I think it's a learning journey.
You know you you you don't know what you don't know and and sometimes you do something and you create something out of like really wanting to do well and wanting to offer a great thing but then if the response isn't good then you just need to pivot and see like okay why isn't it good for them and then because obviously like you don't want to wait run a whole seminar and then no one is actually attending it.
Yeah no I agree that makes a lot of sense especially on the sort of pivoting piece.
I think you can sort of think one thing, especially if you're only exposed to one market and then you go out to a bunch of others and it's just like I have a couple of uh more questions but I think we've mainly sort of gone through the main parts of what I wanted to speak to you about and I want to keep some time for your questions if you have any.
So um over to you really any any questions you have anything that you've heard today that you weren't expecting to hear or uh yeah any anything really happy to answer anything.
Perfect um so Lauren already explained a little bit about the role and um she also shared like there's a lot of like um flexibility kind of like an role like you said about making it your own being curious kind of like shaping the role itself is there um any like boundaries on that is there anything like that you it's like those are the main points that you're looking for or is it kind of like you you are looking at um it's kind of like yeah whatever I could come up with my own like solutions and ways of thinking about it and then offering new ways of like how do we work together?
Yeah exact um it's a good question.
So sort of like what's the main the main problems to solve and are there any sort of boundaries and guardrails that we're like please don't do that.
I I like you say I don't know I we don't know what we don't know yet.
I don't think we have any large guardrails obviously um it's a a product operations role uh within the AI team so it's probably fairly unlikely that you would be building apps or uh doing any of that um but in terms of what we are looking for and hoping for is yeah that sort of operations brain to just come in and go we we could be using this framework or this methodology or something that help us sort of just go, great, wonderful, take that tool.
This helps us supercharges us.
Um and so there's that piece of how can we standardize and productize what we're doing?
There's also the how do we track and measure impact and ROI?
So well not ROI really, but value that we're gonna bring to the business and how can we communicate those success stories out?
Um so there's sort of that outward facing piece as well, which often when there's work to be done gets left by the wayside.
But uh I would say that there's no golden goose that you could kill.
Like there's nothing there's nothing that we're all quite well, we're all very open to change, doing things differently.
There's nothing, there's no process that we're all like, no, we really want to do that.
There's some things that we have set up that seem to be working well, like a a weekly week overview for an hour on a Monday and then sort of 20 minute stand-ups, very sort of like like a self-style an hour check-in with our developers for the Bower AI chat product that we talked about.
So the product and strategy team talking to the developers, that's an hour a week, and those seem to be working well to facilitate communication and focus in on one thing, but there's no reason why if someone wants to come into the team and say, I think have we tried this, we're sort of all happy to try new things, experiment.
Like you say, it might be that one of the experiments doesn't work and we pivot and change it.
But but there's no, I think, to answer your question.
I don't think there's any sort of massive guardrails of things that we have to keep.
There's just things that we have to report and things that we have to do, like in any team.
Does that do that help?
Does that answer that?
That's how that it does, it does.
And um with that, like if I were to comment on your team like tomorrow, what would be like the biggest issue that you're trying to solve?
I think it's probably the like mechanism.
Mobilization of our roadmap, getting our getting it to a point where it's sort of any one of the three of the product team can just go to a project, pick it up.
There's sort of a playbook of standard things.
Um and it's like that that standardization of process would be good, but it would also be good to sort of almost like standardise a project tracker.
We don't have a standard project we don't have a standard set of comms that we sort of put out to stakeholders.
So from my experience and my opinion is that the project experience for stakeholders on the business could vary wildly between if I'm running it, if another project product manager's running it's running it.
So it's not a sort of standard experience for the person that's working with us.
And as such you end up with certain stakeholders liking people in the team and sort of wanting more of their time which is great if the person has the time to give so I think that that would be like the first thing that would be great to sort of get your read on sort of sit down look through roadmap.
This is how we're approaching stuff so far and maybe we'd look at three different sorts of projects and get you could sort of start to look at you know what could be common across all of them.
So I think that's number one and then probably very close second is the comms and impact reporting doing it in a standard way and just getting a regular cadence of that and then if that's set up and running great.
Yeah you know okay okay that makes sense that makes sense and um the team is obviously split up in two regions like um the engineers based in Poland and you guys in London how much is like communicated with vendor team is it just like a lot of like chatted through like email is there a lot of calls or how how is how is everyone like kind of like keeping together yeah so again great questions just writing down um so currently uh we have the sort of ceremonies is a strong word but similar to like an agile ceremonies where you've got the stand ups and things like that so that's uh uh a weekly thing we also have like uh teams so we've got several channels of channels for different projects channels for just the product team channels for the whole team um and so like communication is done kind of quite ad hoc in that sense we obviously have the staple meetings around a specific thing so focusing in on a project focusing in on a product um is the main ways of communication we also travel so um another part of this role would be sort of organizing I think once or twice a year we're gonna get together either in Poland or London or one of the third countries go there and work on a problem for like two three days um so Pavel who's our R D lead he'll be in London uh the first week of Feb for a whole two weeks so then we can communicate and work in person with him when his engineers start we'll probably go over to Warsaw and just meet in person so um a mix essentially does that help that it does it does make because um sometimes we are we've got everyone in London but I'm also like communicated a lot with like my manager they are based in in a park in Tokyo so it's always like you know like like kind of like that it is it is so it's always like okay when I come in I get like a bunch of emails and being like oh okay and then when she comes in she gets a bunch of emails and just keeping track of like and keeping each other as well aligned you know and um I think it's always important to like overcommunicate if the whole team isn't based in one region.
Um so that makes that makes sense.
I totally agree with that I think yeah I mean that sounds like you have a fair amount of uh learning learning from that perspective so yeah it would be super interesting to talk about that and um I think there's the the balance to be faced so that the issues that Pavel and Catherine face is you know a complete wall of unread messages 200 million emails a day a diary full of calls so my job as the senior product and delivery manager would be to essentially do the day to day running of the team then what they need to know anything decisions and feed down so yeah be super interesting to hear your thoughts on what's worked well on that yeah yeah absolutely um and then just one last question in obviously the team is kind of new but I will be interested to know like what kind of like was it what was a project that you worked on that you quite enjoyed working on uh so uh so yeah this is a good question I like discussion um um the thing that I like or the thing that I've always aimed for in my career I did a my first job was as an apprentice in Google, and they asked us what is your career goal, and everyone was like, I want a yacht, I want a map, I've wondered and I wear it, I want variety because I get very bored, and there's like innate fear of being pigeonholed.
So uh I don't know why.
Something deep in my psychology, perhaps.
But the um nice thing about the this job is I might be working on securing an enterprise license for a tool, I might be working on a training program, I might be delivering a workshop, I might be speaking at an event, I might be scoping out a thing, I might be building front end, I might be doing all sorts of things.
The one that I've liked previously uh was the design and build of Bar AI chat.
Like my background is I've got a degree in digital design before this I worked at an agency, and I did pretty much all of the websites for every visitor attraction in London.
So uh London Zoo, Royal Museums of Greenwich, South Bank Center, they're all my designs.
I think they're still there, which is good.
Um so it was nice to sort of get back into less talking about stuff and actually sitting down and going, right?
Well, how is this thing gonna work?
Designing it, branding it, building it, and then choosing a tech stack and then putting it all together at the end.
Um making that's sort of a nice that's for me one of my favorite things is making something.
Doesn't matter what it is, it's just making a thing, um, and seeing it sort of go and be successful and launch.
So um I get a lot of satisfaction out of actually putting a tangible thing together and going, look destroy it team because you know okay, very interesting.
Cool, perfect, thank you.
Um and then sorry, it just popped up in my head.
I thought something that I found quite interesting was um in the in the job spec that Lauren sent, yes, uh it meant that basically to put as well, like the AI, not strategy, but whatever you guys are doing in in the AI department to kind of also share it with like kind of like the broader world to shape that space within the AI communic community, if I read that correctly.
And I thought that was quite interesting.
And I was wondering if um there was already something in place, like for example, I don't know, uh AI uh like meetups, like that's something that happens a lot in in London, or where the company kind of like puts lunch and learns for even like other um publishing houses or kind of like bringing people together within the AI space.
Yes, uh so sort of that outward facing industry phase, yeah.
Uh nothing, nothing so far.
We have like we've we're sort of like fairly well connected into like some agencies and stuff in town.
We've never we put on an innovation showcase when the team was previously the innovation team.
Um we've not done any sort of industry event or any of that sort of stuff, but the team was set up.
I joined it Octo uh November, not last year, the year before.
Okay.
So November 2025, and that's pretty much how long it's been going.
Yeah.
Um so it's been like heads down, deliver some value, make sure everyone's happy with us.
And then we can sort of go outside, aren't we?
Yes.
Rather than going outside going, aren't we amazing?
We've done nothing.
Yes.
So yeah, which is one of those things that's on the we want to see.
Mm-hmm.
Cool.
Okay.
That makes sense.
Perfect.
Thank you so much.
Awesome.
Any more for any more?
That's it for the time being.
Perfect.
Okay, well, um, thank you very much for your time.
Uh the the sort of next steps are um if you're successful, the next interview would be uh I believe it's an in-person interview sometime next week.
I believe it's Mondays, Tuesdays.
Um I will take this, the transcript.
Catherine's also um interviewing concurrently.
So she's doing some got some time uh tomorrow to compare notes and that short list out.
Uh and then we'll go back to Lauren with our feedback and yeah, we'll be in touch.
Okay, amazing.
Well, thank you so much for your time.
Have a lovely day.
You too.
Love you too.
Thank you.
Bye bye.